Guide to the Los Angeles punk collection, 1982-1992.
Los Angeles punk collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Los Angeles punk collection, 1982-1992.
8074
1.2 cubic ft.
Printed material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Archive of material from the Los Angeles punk scene assembled by a passionate music fan between 1982 and 1992.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Archive of material from the Los Angeles punk scene assembled by a passionate music fan between 1982 and 1992. Materials include over 250 flyers, with a half-dozen featuring artwork by Raymond Pettibon; 10 broadsides/posters; 40 band-related stencils that were likely used to decorate band gear, performance space or posters; more than 55 punk magazines, both amateur and professionally produced; nearly a dozen stickers of punk bands; over 50 ticket stubs for shows at various venues around L.A.; and other assorted ephemera including political and religious handouts distributed to show attendees.
The music represented ranges from original Los Angeles bands (The Dickies and X) to pioneering hardcore bands (Circle Jerks, The Middle Class, Wasted Youth, The Mentors, and T.S.O.L.), crossover thrash (Suicidal Tendencies and D.I.), altrock/punk (The Red Hot Chili Peppers, Bad Religion, and Social Distortion), and a few mainstream recording artists who visited the L.A. area (David Bowie, Pink Floyd, James Lee Hooker, and Deep Purple).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pettibon, Raymond, 1957-
Subjects:
Punk culture -- California -- Los Angeles.; Punk culture; Punk rock music.; Punk rock music; Punk rock musicians.; Popular culture -- California -- Los Angeles.
Form and Genre Terms:
Ephemera.; Ticket stubs.; Fliers (printed matter); Stencils (tools)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Music Event Flyers (8.5" x 5.5") (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Music Event Flyers (8.5" x 11") (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Music Event Flyers (8.5" x 11") (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Band Stickers (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Music-related Advertisements (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Fan club membership forms, ads movies, band merchandise (e.g. Kiss Army Paraphernalia), t-shirt and record store flyers
- Political / Social Flyers (8.5" x 11") (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Bovine Gazette" issues, October 1993 - May 1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Satirical social-political publication, based out of Pasadena, CA.
- "Ben is Dead" magazine, December 1991 and Summer 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Satirical social-political magazine, based out of Southern California.
- Political / Social periodicals (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Scott Cooper poetry / Golden Hour Press catalogs (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes: handwritten note from Discord Records founder and Minor Threat drummer, Jeff Nelson, "Back Care" pamphlet, Alcoholics Anonymous pamphlet, graphic photographs of a dead woman - two computer printouts, Westley Allan Dodd mug shots, laminated image of Charles Manson
- "Maximum Rock N Rock" magazine, January - September 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "Maximum Rock N Rock" magazine, October 1983 - April 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- "Flipside Fanzine" (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "Destroy LA" fanzine, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Issues 3 and 4 (2 copies)
- "We Got Power!" magazine (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Issues 2 and 3
- "Ripper" magazine (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Issues 6, 7, and 8
- "60 Miles North" magazine, September 1984 - February 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Volumes 1 and 2
- Misc. Music Magazines (I) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Misc. Music Magazines (II) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Other Magazines (Box 2, Folder 10)
  "Half-Truth" lifestyle magazine, "Alarums and Excursions" live-action role playing magazine, "L.A. Oops" humor paper
- Ticket stubs (I) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Ticket stubs (II) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Music Event Flyers (4.25" x 5.5") (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Music Event Flyers (8.5" x 14") (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Album Flyers (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Political / Social Flyers (8.5" x 11") (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Oversized posters (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Music newspapers (Box 3, Folder (loose))
  Includes: "K News," "Bam," "New Vinyl Times," "Boston Rock," and "Terminal."
- Stencils and text prints for music flyers (Box 4, Folder 1)